biolifeplasma.com 2003-04-02

# Privacy Policy

|  | 

Privacy Policy 

INTRODUCTION 

Thank you for visiting biolifeplasma.com. This Site is owned and operated by Baxter and BioLife Plasma Services. For purposes of the policy, references to "BioLife," "we," "our," and "us" mean Baxter.

This Site provides a wide range of information to our Site's visitors, including information about plasma donation and our related products and services. Like many web sites, we also collect information from our visitors, including personally identifiable information (your full name, e-mail address, phone number) and non-personally identifiable information (e.g., aggregate statistics about what parts of our Site are most popular). This privacy policy is designed to tell you about our information collection practices at this Site – that is, the ways we collect information; what kinds of information we collect; why we collect information; how we use information we collect; with whom we share information we collect; how you can access, amend, and delete information we collect from you; and what kinds of security we use to protect information you provide.

Before using this Site – and particularly before submitting personally identifiable information via this Site – you should read this entire policy. Use of this Site constitutes your agreement to the terms of this policy. If the terms and conditions of the policy are not acceptable to you, do not submit any personally identifiable information via this Site and continue to schedule donations by telephone or during a visit to your Baxter BioLife Plasma Services center.

SCOPE OF POLICY 

Please be aware that this policy applies only to this Site. Within this Site, you may see links or references to other web sites, such as our online incentives partner, MyPoints.com, which are not covered by this policy and are likely to have different information practices. We therefore encourage you to read the privacy policy of each web site you visit. We provide these references and links for your convenience; they should not be construed as an endorsement of such sites, their content, or their information practices. You are solely responsible for any interactions you may have with such web sites.

ACTIVE INFORMATION COLLECTION 

This Site collects information from its visitors in two ways: actively and passively. **Active information collection** refers to instances in which we gather information from you when you fill it in and send it to us, such as by completing a registration form, signing up for an electronic newsletter, or sending us a message via an e-mail reply mechanism provided by this Site. Active information collection can include both personally identifiable information (e.g., your full name or information that is unique to you) and non-personally identifiable information (e.g., if we were to ask for your first name and a list of the top three things you like about our Site). **Passive information collection** refers to instances in which we collect information from you that you have not actively provided (please see the next section of this policy for a summary of our passive information collection practices).

Below, we have summarized the primary means of active information collection at BioLife. By submitting such information at these various information collection points, you specifically consent to the collection, use, and dissemination of such information in accordance with this policy. At each of BioLife’s active information collection points, we have marked which information is required and which is optional. Unless otherwise specified below, failure to provide required information might mean that you cannot participate in the identified activity nor have access to the site. Failure to provide optional information will not prevent your participation in the identified activity or prevent your access to the site, but it may inhibit our ability to customize the Site for you and better understand your interests and needs.

**Registration Information**

If you are interested in receiving electronic updates, alerts, and other information from us regarding this Site and our products and services, you must provide us with an e-mail address. If you prefer to receive such information at home via postal delivery, you must provide us with your home address. In completing your registration, we may also ask for optional information, such as your occupation, to help us better serve you in the future.

**Feedback Information**

We welcome your comments and feedback regarding this Site and our products, services and programs. This Site provides an **e-mail reply mechanism** that permits you to send us your own e-mail address, comments, and any other information you choose to include. **E-mail submitted may not be secure. As a result, you should carefully consider what information you wish to send to us via e-mail.**

This Site posts a feedback form for you to use in submitting comments; we will typically ask you to provide personally identifiable information such as your name, e-mail address, and comments, as well as occupational and demographic information. The feedback form may also ask you to respond to questions regarding your Internet usage habits and how you found this Site. We use the information you decide to send us to follow up with you regarding your comments, improve our products and services, and better understand our donors. Information you provide in a feedback form is typically all optional, though you will need to provide us with contact information if you would like us to send a response.

**Inquiry Forms/Requests for Information**

If you would like to request more information about our products and services, this Site provides special inquiry forms, which typically require you to provide us with your full name, e-mail address, and postal address. In addition, we may ask for other kinds of information, including your phone number, your profession, and the name of your company. We may also ask you to for optional information, such as the ways in which you currently donate plasma. This information is used to respond to your inquiries and to better understand our donors’ needs.

**Calculations and Conversions**

This Site offers you a tool for quickly calculating how much monetary compensation and if you choose to opt in, how many points you may earn based on how frequently you choose to donate plasma. This tool is provided for your convenience, and the calculations you conduct on the site are not transmitted to or recorded by Baxter, nor will it be disclosed to any third party.

PASSIVE INFORMATION COLLECTION 

We may use special technologies to passively collect information while you are visiting BioLife (that is, you do not actively provide this information). These technologies allow us to collect certain kinds of non-personally identifiable information, including your Internet domain name, the type of web browser you use, the operating system you use, the date and time you visit BioLife, the specific pages you visit, and the address of the web site you visited prior to entering BioLife. We do not link this passively collected non-personally identifiable information with personally identifiable information you have actively provided elsewhere on this Site unless requested by a donor for the purpose of error-checking BioLife for the requesting donor only. We reserve the right to share with third parties, including our business partners and advertisers, the anonymous aggregated information that we have passively collected via this Site.

Below we have summarized the primary means of passive information collection at our Site.

**Cookies**

This Site uses cookies, which are small text files that store non-personally identifiable information about you, either temporarily in connection with your Internet Protocol (IP) address (known as a temporary or session cookie, and deleted once you close your browser window) or more permanently on the hard drive of your computer (known as a permanent or persistent cookie). **This Site uses session cookies so that you do not have to fill in the same information from page to page within BioLife. If you elect not to receive cookies, you will continue to be able to schedule plasma donations by calling your donor center or scheduling in person. However, you will not be able to participate in our incentive program with MyPoints.com.**

**Internet Protocol (IP) Addresses**

This Site uses Internet protocol (IP) addresses. IP addresses are unique identifiers automatically assigned to each computer when logging onto the Internet. IP addresses allow us to collect much of the same information we collect through cookies, including browser type, what pages you visit, and how long you stay on the Site. In general, IP addresses allow us to identify problems with our servers, prepare aggregate demographic information and other information regarding this use of this Site, and improve the functions of this Site.

WHAT WE DO WITH YOUR INFORMATION 

The personally identifiable information we collect from you will only be used and disclosed in accordance with this policy or as specifically disclosed to you at the time you provide the information. We will not sell, lease, transfer, share, or otherwise permit access to your personally identifiable information with any third parties other than as described in this policy. In order to redeem BioLife points that you have earned you must provide us with your e-mail address and some basic demographic information which will be provided to MyPoints.com, Inc. We reserve the right to sell, lease, transfer, or otherwise share without restriction aggregated, de-identified, and other non-personally identifiable information regarding site usage, sales, traffic patterns, demographics, and other statistics about our Site or those from whom we collect information via BioLife. We reserve the right to use or disclose personal information provided via this Site as necessary to respond to your requests, comply with applicable laws, regulations, legal processes, and law enforcement inquiries, as required by litigation, to take precautions against liability, and protect the security and integrity of the Site and the safety of its users.

OPTING OUT 

We do not seek to collect personally identifiable information from you that you do not want collected. Toward that end, we indicate at all active information collection points whether requested information is required or optional. We also attempt to tell you at the point of collection and in this policy what the consequences will be (e.g., inability to access important functions of the Site, less tailoring of information to match your interests, etc.) if you do not provide the required or optional information. When you submit personally identifiable information via this Site, whether such information is required or optional, you consent to its disclosure and use in accordance with this privacy policy. If you ever decide that you do not wish to receive information from us regarding our products and services, you may opt out of receiving this information by contacting us by e-mail at [webmaster@baxter.com](mailto:webmaster@baxter.com) or by mail at **BioLife Plasma Services, Attention: Marketing, 1435 Lake Cook Road, Deerfield, IL 60015.**

INFORMATION ACCESS 

We take reasonable steps to ensure that personally identifiable information that you send us via this Site is accurate, current, and complete. Toward that end, we provide you with reasonable access to your personal information to correct errors or delete the information you have provided. If you wish to correct or delete your personally identifiable information, please contact us by e-mail at [webmaster@baxter.com](mailto:webmaster@baxter.com) or by mail at **BioLife Plasma Services, Attention: Marketing, 1435 Lake Cook Road, Deerfield, IL 60015.**

To respond to your request or inquiry, we may require follow-up or contact information to allow us to verify that you are the person authorized to view the information you are requesting. We may, at our discretion, refuse to allow you access to certain information if, in our view, to provide such access would jeopardize another person's privacy; would violate any applicable federal, state, or foreign law, regulation, or directive; or would unreasonably burden this Site.

DATA SECURITY 

Although we take reasonable steps to protect the personally identifiable information that you provide via this Site, no system is 100% secure or error-free. Therefore, we do not, and cannot, guarantee the security or accuracy of the information we gather.

One way we protect your personally identifiable information is through usernames and passwords. This safety measure is only effective if you protect the secrecy of both your username and password. If you ever suspect your username or password may have been compromised or subject to unauthorized use, contact us immediately at [webmaster@baxter.com](mailto:webmaster@baxter.com).

THIS SITE IS NOT INTENDED FOR USE BY CHILDREN 

This Site is not directed to, and does not seek to collect personally identifiable information from, children under the age of 13. Nevertheless, if we are informed that we have collected information from someone in this age category, we will take reasonable steps to delete that information.

CONTACT US / ENFORCEMENT OF PRIVACY POLICY 

If you have any questions, comments, concerns or complaints about this Policy or the information practices of this Site, you can submit an inquiry via Baxter’s online Privacy Complaint Form, call 1-800-422-9837 (U.S.) or 847-948-4770 (outside of the U.S.), fax your inquiry to 847-948-3642, or send us mail at **BioLife Plasma Services, Attention: Marketing, 1435 Lake Cook Road, Deerfield, IL 60015.**

We will take reasonable steps to respond to your inquiry and remedy problems you bring to our attention.

CHANGES TO THIS POLICY 

We reserve the right to change this Policy at any time and in our sole discretion. If we do change the Policy, the new Policy will be posted here, along with its revision date, and all information collected following the posting of such changes will be subject to the new Policy. We want you to know, however, that before we use or disclose your previously collected personally identifiable information in a materially different manner from that to which you agreed, we will first secure your affirmative consent for such use or disclosure. Absent such consent, we will **use your personally identifiable information in accordance with the Policy in effect at the time we collected the information.** In the event that you do not consent to the terms and conditions of the new Policy, you may continue to schedule donations by calling the BioLife Plasma Services center near you. We encourage you to check this Policy periodically and – at a minimum – before each instance in which you provide personally identifiable information via this Site.

This policy was last revised on July 2, 2002.
